In the last lecture I hinted at this term called the project initiation context.
Basically why are projects created.
Well we know other projects are created why because they create and I hope he said it at least in your
mind business how you were doing a project to generate some benefit.
That's the only reason why we do a project.
Now you might say well we have to do a project because of the law.
Well the benefit is you do the project because of the law.
So you don't go to jail or fines or regulations.
So there are benefits by even a hearing to the law if you want to do the project.
It's better to do the project than usually have to pay a fine or break the law.
And I say usually and not to get off on a tangent here but sometimes that's it's easier and better to
pay a fine and have to adhere to regulation.
I think always asking somebody what to do and certainly can't continue to do that.
But there are those instances.
All right.
That's an aside.
Let's get back on our main thought here of the project initiation contacts that projects create business
value.
So there are four things that we need to know about the business now you and projects.
First off we do it because of the just mentioned regulatory legal or social requirements that we are
obligated to do the project.
But there's still business value as you know in that obligation stakeholder requests the customer ask
us to create something for them.
So that was a good example of those organizations that they do projects for others for profit.
So we get a stakeholder request could be internal we're a stakeholder comes to your department the IP
department and they want you to do it update or to swap out their laptops or whatever the case may be
technological advances.
So you're on Windows X and you really feel like Windows y is a better software operating system to be
on and that that is something you want to implement as a project so there's an advance in technology
now technological advances for our exam.
Does that mean just hardware software data network.
We could be talking about a technological advance in a piece of equipment in a manufacturing environment
or a construction environment or a new advanced and a type of material that you use in your discipline.
So it's not always just hardware software it's the technology and the improvement.
Step Number Four or the fourth option are really a step about why a project is created.
If you're going to create improve or fix existing products processes or services so member our Mac team
move add change delete.
So you are creating improving or fixing a process or service or something that's existing.
Moving from that current state to the desired future state.
So this is that puts it in context of why are we doing this project.
Put it in context put it in light of regulations.
It's a stakeholder request.
It's an advanced technology or we're creating some new product service or solution.
All right great job.
I'll see you in the next lecture.